Guide to the Tara Association (New Jersey) Records AIA.078
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tara Association (New Jersey) Records
1971-2014
AIA.078
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
1.0 linear feet in 1 record carton
The Tara Association was founded in Milltown, New Jersey 1971 by Pat Flynn, Maura Geraghty, Peggy Cuddy-Bojitas, and Phyllis Powell. The Tara Association is dedicated to the preservation of Irish heritage, including the arts, poetry, literature, drama, folklore, and the Irish language. In June 2014, the Tara Association ceased activities. This collection contains flyers, meeting minutes, membership logs, and research material produced or collected by the Tara Association documenting its activities and objectives to preserve Irish heritage and arts.
Tara Association.
Related Archival Materials
Gaelic Society Records (AIA 025)
Custodial History note
This collection was donated by Phyllis Powell on behalf of the Tara Association through Miriam Nyhan at NYU's Glucksman Ireland House in November 2014. The materials were transferred from Ireland House to the Archives of Irish America in May of 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.026.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains flyers, meeting minutes, membership logs, and research material produced or collected by the Tara Association documenting its activities and objectives to preserve Irish heritage and arts.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tara Association was founded in Milltown, New Jersey 1971 by Pat Flynn, Maura Geraghty, Peggy Cuddy-Bojitas, and Phyllis Powell. The organization has grown from an original group of 25 to over 200 members. The Tara Association is dedicated to the preservation of Irish heritage, including the arts, poetry, literature, drama, folklore, and the Irish language. The name is based on the Hill of Tara, the ritual site of ancient high kings in Ireland. In June 2014, the Tara Association ceased activities.
Appraisal note
Extensive duplicates and some widely available publications present in the donation were discarded.
Irish Americans |x Ethnic identity.; Irish Americans |x Music.; Irish Americans |x Societies, etc.; Irish language |z United States
- Artwork for Flyers and Publications, 1972-2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Certificates of Appreciation, 1972-2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Comhaltas Ceoltoiri Eireann, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Constitution and Founding Documents, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Dance, 1971-2014 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Dinner Dance Programs, 1981-1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Events for Area or Affiliated Organizations, 1977-2014 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Financial Records, 1990-2011 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Genealogical Research, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Irish Language Mass, 1984-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Meeting Minutes, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Meeting Minutes, 1994-2014 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Membership Applications, 1972-2014 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Membership Log, 1971-2014 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Newsletters, 1974-2014 (Box 1, Folder 16-19)
- Photographs, 1971-2014 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Phyllis Powell Farewell, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Recipes, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Songs and Poetry, 1971-2014 (Box 1, Folder 23)